American Congregational Association records, 1846-2022.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Building records, 1846 2019; 1846-2019; 165 Folders; 9 Volumes; 9 Boxes
  - Assessments and reports, 1871 2019; 1871-2019; 26 Folders
    - Building evaluation, 2000 2001; 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Limestone degredation assessment, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Alley status report, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Building environmental assessment, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Building appraisal, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Building appraisal, 2004 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Building inspection report, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Fire safety, 2007 2008; 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Energy assessment, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Balfour property report, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Fire protection system report, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Building environmental assessment, 2017 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Hazardous materials survey, 2019 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Building history, 1872 1998; 1872-1998; 9 Folders
    This subseries contains records related to the history of the Congregational House at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts, as well as the Somerset Building. This series contains articles, newspaper clippings, anniversary programs, and records related to the Kansas City statement of faith plaque that adorns the Congregational House's front entrance.
    - Congregational House newspaper articles, 1872 1898; 1872-1898 (Folder 8)
    - Architectural histories and articles, 1897 1984; 1897-1984 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Congregational House dedication and programs, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Congregational House dedication and programs, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Kansas City statement of faith 50th anniversary records, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Kansas City plaque, 1963 1968; 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - National Register of Historic Places documents, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Building plaques, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Congregational House 100th anniversary, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1872 2005; 1872-2005; 11 Folders
    This subseries contains general correspondence about the buildings variously controlled by the American Congregational Association including the Congregational House at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts, and the Somerset building. A majority of the correspondence in this subseries is related to Frank D. Bradley.
    - Somerset building legal correspondence, 1872 1884; 1872-1884 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Congregational House construction correspondence, 1897 1898; 1897-1898 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Athenaeum legal documents, 1897 1898; 1897-1898 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - William Cobb building correspondence, 1897 1920; 1897-1920 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Frank D. Bradley correspondence, A-B, 1947 1955; 1947-1955 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Frank D. Bradley correspondence, C-M, 1947 1955; 1947-1955 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Frank D. Bradley correspondence, Otis Elevator Company, 1947 1955; 1947-1955 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Frank D. Bradley correspondence, P-Z, 1947 1955; 1947-1955 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Athenaeum correspondence, 1992 2004; 1992-2004 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Preservation agreement and correspondence, 1998 2005; 1998-2005 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Tenancy and rents, 1873 2010; 1873-2010; 16 Folders; 8 Volumes
    This subseries contains records related to the tenants of the Congregational House at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts. The majority of the records within this subseries are related to the collection of rents, though the subseries also contains records related to disputes with tenants, such as legal actions taken against some tenants.
    - Rents received, 1873 1879; 1873-1879 (Box 9, Volume 1)
    - Rents received, 1879 1896; 1879-1896 (Box 9, Volume 2)
    - Rents, 1885 1888; 1885-1888 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Congregational House property agreements, 1897 1898; 1897-1898 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Rent book, 1898 1901; 1898-1901 (Box 9, Volume 3)
    - Rent book, 1902 1903; 1902-1903 (Box 9, Volume 4)
    - Rent book, 1912 1921; 1912-1921 (Box 9, Volume 5)
    - Rents, 1916 1919; 1916-1919 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Rent book, 1919 1922; 1919-1922 (Box 16, Volume 1)
    - Tenants, 1924 1997; 1924-1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Legal actions against National Society of Puritan Decendants, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Rent book, 1932 1941; 1932-1941 (Box 16, Volume 2)
    - Tenant roster, 1932 1970; 1932-1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Legal actions against Cornelius Parker, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Legal actions against John Littlefield, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Rent book, 1957 1976; 1957-1976 (Box 16, Volume 3)
    - Thomas Todd Printers, 1961 1974; 1961-1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Tenants, 1967 2004; 1967-2004 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Equalization requisition no. 147 letter, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Boston Bar Association, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - General Theological Library, 1986 1987; 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Rental analyses, 2003 2008; 2003-2008 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - List of tenants, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Club House estate opinion, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Architectural drawings, 1897 2019; 1897-2019; 30 Folders; 9 Boxes
    This subseries contains architectural drawings for the Congregational House, both exterior and interior, at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts.
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 10)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 11)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 12)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 13)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 14)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 15)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 16)
    - Congregational House structural drawings, 1897 (Folder 17)
    - Plans of land, 1897 (Folder 18)
    - Congregational House drawings, 1897 (Folder 19)
    - Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge architectural drawings, circa 1897 (Folder 20)
    - Congregational House drawings, circa 1897 (Folder 21)
    - Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge architectural drawings, circa 1898 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Architectural drawings, 1920 1959; circa 1920-1959 (Folder 22)
    - Floor plans, 1993 2017; 1993-2017 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Sidewalk repair drawings, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Building anchorage and ironwork drawings, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Architectural drawings, 2000 2009; circa 2000-2009 (Folder 23)
    - Infrastructure upgrade project drawings, 2003 (Folder 1)
    - Infill project drawings, 2003 (Folder 2)
    - Tenant layout drawings, 2004 (Folder 3)
    - Library enhancement project drawings, 2004 (Folder 4)
    - Library enhancement project drawings, 2005 (Folder 5)
    - Proposed library expansion, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Infill project drawings, 2006 (Folder 6)
    - Masonry repair project drawings, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Stairwell enclosure drawings, 2014 (Folder 24)
    - Renovation project drawings, 2019 (Folder 25)
    - Proposed roof plan, undated (Folder 7)
    - Architectural drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous architectural drawings, undated (Box 31)
  - Building management records, 1897 2011; 1897-2011; 9 Folders
    This subseries contains records related to the management of the Congregational House at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts. Especially prevalent within this subseries are records related to 3rd party vendors the American Congregational Association contracted with to handle the management of the building.
    - Work orders, 1897 1898; 1897-1898 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Charge of corruption against building superintendent, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Management contracts, 1928 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Compass management file, 1994 1995; 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Maintenance concerns, 1994 2005; 1994-2005 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Architectural Heritage Foundation proposal, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Architectural Heritage Foundation communications, 2008 2009; 2008-2009 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Architectural Heritage Foundation reports, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Architectural Heritage Foundation contracts, 2009 2011; 2009-2011 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Renovations and construction projects, 1897 2016; 1897-2016; 42 Folders
    This subseries contains records related to various construction and renovation projects the American Congregational Association undertook to maintain and expand the Congregational House at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts. This subseries contains correspondence, reports, contractor proposals, and supporting documentation and specifications for various construction projects. This series also contains records related to preservation agreements for the building with the state of Massachusetts. Records related specifically to renovations and construction projects within the Congregational Library's space, rather than the building at large, may be found in the subseries, "Facilities, 1963-2020," under the series, "Congregational Library & Archives records, 1853-2022."
    - Architect construction agreement, 1897 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Heating renovation, 1977 1979; 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Building renovations, 1994 1999; 1994-1999 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Lobby and sidewalk renovation, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Sidewalk repair project, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Front entrance project, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Tremont Street Preservation Trust renovations, 1996 2000; 1996-2000 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Building conservation project, 1996 2001; 1996-2001 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Preservation restriction correspondence, 1996 2007; 1996-2007 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Preservation project, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Massachusetts Historical Commission preservation project, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Massachusetts Historical Commission preservation agreement, 1997 1999; 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Building conservation project RFP, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Massachusetts Historical Commission preservation agreement, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Conditions assessment recommendations, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Facade restoration project, 1998 2000; 1998-2000 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Iron work project, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Conservation grant application, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Planning study "Alternate D", 2001 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Fire escape repair, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Fire escape repair project, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Infrastructure renovation, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - Elevator renovations, 2002 2005; 2002-2005 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Boiler replacement, 2002 2005; 2002-2005 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Infill project reports, 2002 2003; 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Infill project correspondence, 2003 2006; 2003-2006 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Building enchancement plan, 2003 2004; 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Construction finances, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Enhancement project financial projections, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Office refurbishing project, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Infill project application, 2004 2005; 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Massachusetts Historical Commission renovation, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Fire alarm upgrade, 2005 2006; 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Masonry repair project, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Masonry repair project, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - South side massonry repair project, 2010 2011; 2010-2011 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Infill project proposal, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Library and building enhancement project plan, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Construction proposal, 2012 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Stairwell project, 2014 2015; 2014-2015 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Window report, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Fire alarm installation, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sale of the building records, 1927 2018; 1927-2018; 12 Folders
    This subseries contains records related the possible, or actual, sale of the Congregational House at 14 Beacon Street, Boston, Massachusetts. The American Congregational Association long grappled with the idea of selling the building. The association nearly sold the building in 2008 but an economic downturn resulted in the buyer pulling out from the deal. The Congregational House was sold to Faros Properties in 2017. This sub-series contains records related to discussions had regarding the sale of the building, information and resources created in the lead up to potential sales of the building, and correspondence and communications from the board of directors about the sale of the building, and the lease the association signed with Faros Properties in the wake of the sale of the building.
    - Sell or keep discussions, 1927 1970; 1927-1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Legal correspondence related to building sale, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Building sale agreement, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Building sale, 2007 2008; 2007-2008 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Building sale correspondence, 2007 2008; 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Prospective building sale plans, 2007 2009; 2007-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Building sale board responses, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - Special mailings for sale of building, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Building sale, 2012 2017; 2012-2017 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Building sale publicity packet, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Building sale closing documents, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Faros lease, 2018 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Congregational Library & Archives records, 1853 2022; 1853-2022; 155 Folders; 9 Volumes
  This series contains records related to the Congregational Library & Archives and its various functions such as external communications, fundraising, and the administration and everyday functions of the Library itself. This series also contains records about the collections held by the Library as well as some records related to the Congregational Christian Historical Society. The Congregational Library & Archives has always been the primary function of the American Congregational Association's work, and after the sale of the Congregational House in 2017, became the sole focus of the ACA.
  - General correspondence, 1853 2004; 1853-2004; 12 Folders
    This subseries contains correspondence related to the Congregational Library & Archives, especially correspondence from former librarians, such as Isaac Langworthy and Hal Worthley.
    - Correspondence, 1853 1858; 1853-1858 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Joseph Clark correspondence, 1857 1858; 1857-1858 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Isaac P. Langworthy correspondence, 1865 1879; 1865-1879 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Francis Allen correspondence, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - John Harper correspondence, 1959 1961; 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Harold Worthley correspondence, 1978 1979; 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Harold Worthley correspondence, 1980 1984; 1980-1984 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Harold Worthley correspondence, 1985 1987; 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Harold Worthley correspondence, 1987 1989; 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Harold Worthley correspondence, 1997 1999; 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Harold Worthley correspondence, 1994 2004; 1994-2004 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Margaret Bendroth correspondence, 2003 2004; 2003-2004 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Library and archives records, 1854 2016; 1854-2016; 36 Folders; 8 Volumes
    This subseries contains records related to the administration and everyday functions of the Congregational Library & Archives. This subseries contains policy documents, records related to former librarians, especially Isaac Langworthy and Hal Worthley, library account books, and select records about former staff.
    - Isaac Langworthy notebook, 1854 1880; 1854-1880 (Box 14, Volume 2)
    - Library insurance and related correspondence, 1892 1897; 1892-1897 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Alonzo Quint daybook, 1894 1896; 1894-1896 (Box 14, Volume 3)
    - Wages and staff shortages related to World War II, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Librarian retirements and pensions, 1946 1958; 1946-1958 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Librarian's reports, 1956 1964; 1956-1964 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Library account book, 1961 1963; 1961-1963 (Box 14, Volume 4)
    - Library account book, 1962 1969; 1962-1969 (Box 14, Volume 5)
    - Library account book, 1966 1969; 1966-1969 (Box 14, Volume 6)
    - Library account book, 1969 1974; 1969-1974 (Box 14, Volume 7)
    - Library account book, 1974 1976; 1974-1976 (Box 14, Volume 8)
    - CLA classification system, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Evelyn Vrandenburgh, 1971 2000; 1971-2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Harold Worthley writings, 1975 2001; 1975-2001 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Personnel policy, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Policy correspondence, 1978 1989; 1978-1989 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - John Harrer, 1981 1985; 1981-1985 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Library policies, 1981 2008; 1981-2008 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Disaster plan, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Archival collecting and accessions policy, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - NEDCC preservation grant, 1983 2006; 1983-2006 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Library insurance, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Mormon microfilm project, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Statistics, 1989 2002; 1989-2002 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Archive policies, 1991 2006; 1991-2006 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Records management program, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Archives processing manual, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Deaccession policy discussion, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Sexual harassment policy, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Guide to local church records, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Disaster plan, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Archives policies and procedures manual, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Oral history project, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Harold Worthley birthday bash, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Harold Worthley retirement party, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Library guest book, 2005 2006; 2005-2006 (Box 14, Volume 9)
    - Staff retreat, 2007 2009; 2007-2009 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Personnel policies statement, 2007 2010; 2007-2010 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Patron survey, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - First founders project, 2013 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Strategic plan, 2014 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - New York Times article, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Workplace discrimination and harassment policy, 2016 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Book plate, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Development records, 1856 2008; 1856-2008; 23 Folders
    This subseries contains records related to the Congregational Library and Archives's efforts to raise money through donations, bequests, and gifts. Included within this subseries are records related to gifts, bequests, special funds, and fundraising communications.
    - Fundraising letters, 1856 1876; 1856-1876 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Building fund pledge drive, 1872 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Isaac Langworthy estate, 1874 1898; 1874-1898 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - The Pitcher Memorial Fund, 1880 1936; 1880-1936 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Henry Stickney bequest, 1893 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Mary Mitchell bequest, 1901 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fundraising letters, 1911, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Alexander MacKenzie portrait fundraiser, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Beqests, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Gifts, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Financial contribution from ACA, 1930 1931; 1930-1931 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Fundraising letters, 1962 2002; 1962-2002 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Library fundraising campaign, 1964 1965; 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Bequests, 1974 1984; 1974-1984 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Donations, 1978 1989; 1978-1989 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Bequests, 1979 1997; 1979-1997 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Arvel M. Steece fund, 1990 1999; 1990-1999 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Capital funds literature, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - NACCC Missionary Society support, 1996 1999; 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Donations, 1997 2003; 1997-2003 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Stern Memorial Trust, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Fundraising, 2002 2004; 2002-2004 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Fundraising, 2003 2008; 2003-2008 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Communications, 1859 2022; 1859-2022; 10 Folders
    This subseries contains records related to the Congregational Library & Archives's external communications efforts. This subseries contains brochures and pamphlets about the Library, leaflets for programs, publicity publications, and correspondence related to the Bulletin.
    - Congregational Quarterly, 1859 1873; 1859-1873 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Publications, 1931 1953; 1931-1953 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Rare Book Room publicity, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Publications, 1970 1985; 1970-1985 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Program leaflets, 1977 2022; 1977-2022 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Bulletin correspondence, 1978 1999; 1978-1999 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Articles about library and building, 1984 2009; 1984-2009 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Library publicity, 1985 2008; 1985-2008 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Library event programs, 2005 2012; 2005-2012 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Brochures, undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Collections, 1853 2004; 1853-2004; 24 Folders; 1 Volume
    This subseries contains records about the print and manuscript collections held by the Congregational Library & Archives. This subseries contains collection inventories, appraisals, notes about portions of the collections, records relating to the loan of the Johnathan Mayhew portrait to the National Gallery, condition surveys, and records relating to specific collecting projects. Of special import in this subseries is the 1853 book list which contains a list of the first 56 books that were donated to the Congregational Library.
    - Catalog of books belonging to the Congregational Library Association, 1853 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Book lists, 1862 1887; 1862-1887 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Portrait List, circa 1890 (Box 14, Volume 1)
    - Bishop Stubbs collection notes, 1901 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Appraisal and conservation, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Insurance for collections, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Library accession survey, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Portrait lists and appraisals, 1962 1979; 1962-1979 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Portrait appraisals, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Cambridge platform article, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - A Christian covenanting confession restoration, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Mayhew portrait loan, 1973 1976; 1973-1976 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Reading room carpet, 1977 2000; 1977-2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Microfilm projects, 1978 1986; 1978-1986 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Preservation, 1981 1986; 1981-1986 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Cambridge platform loan, 1981 1982; 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Shelf lists, 1981 2001; 1981-2001 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript collections survey, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Microfilm projects, 1993 1997; 1993-1997 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Furniture appraisals, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Collections condition survey, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 29)